Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Benjamin Franklin Miscellaneous Collection, 1710-1793; Mss.B.F85.[numeral]; 531 items
  - Letter to Count de Vergennes from Benjamin Franklin, Silas Deane, Arthur Lee, 1777 December 4; Photostat, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From Facsimile L.C.
  - Letter to his Excellency [Comte de Vergennes ?, ca. 1777-1778; ADr, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Assures him that they have no account of any treaty on foot between America and England. Requests loan of two millions sterling.
    Probably draft of letter sent to Vergennes by the U.S. Commissioners.
  - Plat-pays de Paris, France. Permit for Benjamin Franklin to take wine through customs, 1778 March 10; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    French.
  - Letter to A[rthur] Lee, 1778 March 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Rumor that Adams is to replace Deane.
    Presented by Arthur Bloch, Dec.1936.
  - Letter to Don Juan Emery, Bilbao, 1778 March 23; L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Prizes have been confiscated by France and returned to England. France and the U. S. now have a treaty, and France will aid the U. S.
  - Letter to [Jonathan Williams, 1778? April 18; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Latter is badly stained)
  - Letter to M. Genet, 1778 April 28; ALS, 1p. Seal.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    British finances. Sends resolution of Congress in re Burgeyne's army.
  - Letter to Arthur Lee, 1778 April 5; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Demand for money to aid some prisoners in their journey from Dunkirk.
    Contains draft of Lee's reply, of same date.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 10; Photostat, 2p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    In French.
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar, v.4,407.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin; Wanwick, 1778 May 5; Photostat, 3p.; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794
    Report of Franklin's death. Fears he suffered severe loss during British occupation of Philadelphia. News of family and friends; mentions Mrs. Green.
    Printed in Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography,v.72,no.3,p.267.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1778 May 9; Photostat, 3p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar, v.4,408.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, 1778 June 5; Photostat, 1p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar,v.4,411.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Rush, 1778 June 17; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Mr. [H.] Archer who goes to America as a volunteer in the cavalry.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 17; Photostat, 1p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania;cf. Franklin calendar,v.4,412.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Rush, 1778 June 17; Photocopy of printed L. 1p. 9-3/4x6-1/2.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Henry W. Archer.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1778 June 24; Photostat, 2p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar, v.4,413.
  - Commission to Peter Colomb to serve as captain in the U.S. Army beginning April 6, 1778, 1778 June 30; PrDS, 1p.; U.S. [Continental] Congress
    Seal.
    Issued in lieu of torn document dated April 6, 1778.
    Contains certification signed by B. Franklin as to authenticity of the document; December 20, 1780.
  - Letter to [David Hartley], 1778 June 8; Facsimile of ALS, 1p. 3-3/4x3-3/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Proposed exchange of prisoners.
    From Gotheby Parks Bernet Inc. Sale catalogue Sale no. 3813B November 25, 1975, item 360.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", 1778 June 8; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Refers to earlier letter of May 25. Concerns exchange of 200 English prisoners.
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, 1778 July 2; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges the plan of the hydraulic machine at Chatou.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin]; Vers, [1778] July 10; Photostat, 4p., end.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar,v.4,415.
  - Letter to James Lovell, 1778 July 22; LS Cy, 7p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.7,p.174.
  - Letter to the Council of Massachusetts Bay, 1778 Sept. 9; LS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Encloses a letter from [Thomas] Hutchinson to Dr. Lloyd which they have opened.
    Text of letter probably in the hand of John Adams.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1778 Oct. 22; ALS, 4p.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808
    Family news. High cost of living. Mr. Bache has brought back papers Dr. Franklin left with Mr. Galloway. Trustees of Academy almost all Tories.
    Printed: Journal of the Lancaster County Historical Society, v.61, no.1, pp.24-25.
  - Resolution in re Lt.-Col. Touzard [Louis de Tousard], 1778 October 27; Photocopy of ADS, Charles Thomson. 1p.; U.S. Continental Congress
  - Letter to M. [James ?] Leveux, Calais, 1778 November 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Warns of an English cutter off Dieppe which pretends to be American. Asks that Mr. Collas's things be forwarded to him.
  - Letter to M. de Chaumont, [1778] December 4; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. Transcribes news from America relative to the movement of the British fleet.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 Dec. 4; Photostat, 1p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania; cf. Franklin calendar, v.4,417.
  - Les Ephemeres [The story of the ephemera, in a letter to Mme. Brillon, summer of], 1778; Copy of D. 4p., docketed by BF; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. For two other copies, of. FP 50(1), 39 a and b.
    Printed: Smyth 7, 206.
    see also Livingston, Franklin end his press at Passey p.28.
  - Letter to [Mme. Helvetius], ca. 1778; ADr, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.7,204; also one of Passy press documents, cf. Livingston, 32-34.
    Also printed: Duveen, D.I. and Klickstein, Some occupants of 52 R e d'hutauil... in Journal of the History of Medicine, v.9, no.1, pp.113-114 (in English).
  - Letter to Anne Catherine (de Ligneville d'Autricout) Helvetius, ca.1778; A.L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Bound with this are engravings of Franklin and Mme. Helvetius and reprints from Livingston). Contemporary copy, in another's hand. with interlineations in Franklin's hand.
    For facsimile and study of this bagatelle, see: APS Library Bulletin, 1959, G.Chinard. "Random notes on two "Bagatelles." pp.727-760.
    Printed: Smyth, VII, 204-206.
  - Letter to Capt. Benjamin Gunnison, 1779 January 14; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In re cargo of the Morris.
    Presented by Mrs. William Ernest Smith, Sept. 1953.
    From original in National Archives, Records of the Veterans admin. Doc. from Revolutionary war pension file of James Brown, S 12 282.
  - Letter to [Charles Guillaume Frédéric] Dumas, 1779 February 19; L.S. 3p.and end. Fragments. Various sizes.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, Works, VII, 231.
  - To all Captains and Commanders..., 1779 March 10; D.S. 2p. 12-1/4x7.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Instructs captains of American vessels not to obstruct but rather to facilitate in any way the scientific expedition of Captain Cook.
  - Letter to "the Representatives of the Author of Experiments on the igneous Fluid, 1779 March 13; Copy of ALS 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is honoured by invitation and shall endeavour to be present at "the farther Exhibition of those ingenious Experiments."
    (see also Franklin Papers, vol.44, folios 152, 155, 168.)
  - Letter to David Hartley, 1779 March 21; Facsimile 3p. 9x6-3/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Deceived about "affair of the prisoners." Refers to Dr. Bancroft. Hopes for Peace. Gen. Lincoln and Thompson's southern campaign. Strength of America.
    (From the Rendells, Inc., Cat. 126, May 1977.)
  - Letter to Comte de Vergennes, 1779 March 27; L.S. 2p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Sends a letter from M. Gratien reprizes.
  - Letter to [Jean Paul Maras ?], 1779 March 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Regrets that he could not be present at his curious experiments on Saturday: suggests another date.
  - Letter to Arthur Lee, 1779 April 3; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 7,278.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin]; Paris, 1779 April 14; ALS, 2p.; Lafayette, Marie Jean Paul Joseph Roch Yves Gilbert du Motier, marquis de 1757-1834
    Arrangements for arms and troops. Mentions Mr. Martel.
  - Letter to [Charles Guillaume Frédéric] Dumas, 1779 May 22; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Lack of value of American money.
  - Letter to D. [Johannes] Ingenhause, 1779 May 4, 5; L.S. with A. postscript. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Desires to be brought up-to-date with the volumes of the Transactions [of the Royal Society]. Encloses his thoughts on the Northern Lights, a translation of which was read before the French Academy. Mentions Benjamin Vaughan and Dr. Priestley.
    Printed: Cohen, Franklin and Newton, p.80-81.
  - Letter to M. Le Ray de Chaumont, 1779 August 5; L.S. (?) 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Regarding orders for Capt. Jones.
  - Letter to Dr.Franklin, 1779 Sept. 14; ALS, 6p.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808
    Printed: Letters to B. Franklin... ed. by W. Duane, New York,1859,p.105.
  - Letter to [William] Bingham, 1779 October 4; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks for sending newspapers. Unable to authorize payment of bill. He is limited to drafts made by Congress. Most important to "keep up their Credit line."
  - Letter to [Elizabeth] Partridge, 1779 October 11; Print of A.Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth,v.7,393.
  - Letter to J[oseph] Palmer, 1779 October 27; LS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to Mr. Palmer's nephew who has gone to England. Lafayette is bearer of this letter.
  - Letter to [Robert] Montgomery, 1779 October 28; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Will intercede on his behalf with the Spanish embassador; is surprised at treatment he receives from the Speniards. Mentions Mr. Adams.
    ---- Bloch film, fr.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Passy: London, 1779 Nov. 15; Photocopy, 1p.; Digges, Thomass
    Introduces Mr. Fabroni, "a young Gentleman of distinguished worth from Italy," who"has been some time travelling with His ingenious Friend and Companion Mr. Fontana."
    Original in Univ. of Pennsylvania Library.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1779; A.L. 4p. Draft. 11x9.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808
    Forwards silk for the Queen. Concerning B.F.Bache. Social life. Linens and wool spun. Family news. Refers to Duffield.
  - to Brown, Collinson and Tritton, 1780 January 10; A. Dr. of L.S.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to ---- Woodmason, 1780 January 10; A. Dr. of L.Signed with initials.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Mary] Hewson, 1780 January 10; A.Dr. of L.S.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [William] Strahan, 1780 January 24; 3 ADr.s, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Letter as actually sent is in the Morgan Library; APS has photostat.
    First draft printed: APS Library Bulletin for 1945, p October
    Second and third drafts reproduced: APS Library Bulletin for 1945, p November
  - Letter to Benj[ami]n Franklin, Paris; Dunkirk, 1780 Feb. 1; ALS, 2p.; Lee, Stephen
    Complains of ill-treatment from John Paul Jones. Wishes payment for his services.
  - Promissory note to Ferdinand Grand, 1780 February 15; D.S. 1p. 8x13.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    750,000 livres @5%/year, payable 1 January 1785.
  - Letter to Sally Bache, 1780 March 16; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Silk sent for the Queen is damaged. Sends some of Ben's letters; thinks he is better at Geneva.
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, 1780 April 1; Transcript of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Delivery of arms and gunpowder. Advance of 100,000 livres to be made for Americans of the Alliance and the Bonhomme Richard.
    Transcript made by D.H.Wallace, March 1952.
    From original in Vail mss., Geneva, Switzerland, v.1.p.19.
  - Letters to Mme. la presidente du Meinieres, 1780 April 23; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has promised Mme. Helvetius that he will accompany her on Wednesday next to the Pavillions de Chaillot.
  - Letter to M. [Benjamin] Franklin; Bude, 1780 June 7; ALS, 7p.; ZrenC?, baron
    Transcribes his views on the war in America; offers his services.
  - Will, July 17, 1788; [and] Codicil, 1789 June 23; D.S. 11p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    most of which carry signature of B. Franklin on bottom marginal [in red leather slip case]
    Transferred to custody of APS from Philadelphia Register of wills, by decres of Orphans' Court, June 9, 1953; of.
  - Letter to S. Huntington, 1780 July 10; Photostat of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Arthur Bloch, Dec.1952.
    Original in APS, F.P. v.69, no.6.
    Printed: Smyth, 8,119.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, 1780 July 22; ALS, 3p.; Richard, Bache. 1737-1811
    Heard from him last by Marquis de la Fayette. News of family. Inquires about Ben's schooling. Work of women for American army. Proposal to establish bank.
  - Letter to [James] Woodmason, 1780 July 25; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges receipt of proposals relating to the new-invented art copying; has distributed specimens; and has practised it.
    From original in Assay office, Birmingham, Eng.
  - Letter to [C.W.F. Dumas], 1780 July 26; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 8,121.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin; Paris, 1780 July 26; Photostat, 3p.; Lavoisier, Antoine Laurent, 1743-1794
    Relative to S.Fouquet, maker of gun powder, who has been in America.
    -----Typed c.of L. cc.
    Presented by P.S.duPont, June 1947; from original in Harward univ. library
  - Letter to J[ohn] Jay, Madrid, 1780 July 31; L.S. 1p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has given orders for a credit of£1,000 to be divided between him and Mr. Carmichael. Makes similar advance to Messrs. Adams and Dana. Congratulations on birth of a daughter.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 Sept. 20; Typescript (c.c.) of ALS, 3p.; Logan, George, 1753-1821
    Appreciation for Franklin's attention during his stay in Paris. Affairs in America slowly improving. Is at present librarian of the Loganian library. Presented by Whitfield J. Bell, jr., May 1954.
    From original in Ms. Collection, Richmond Academy of Medicine, Richmond, Va.
  - Letter to M. Dumas, 1780 October 2; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.8,141.
  - Letter to [Jean Paul Marat], 1780 November 24; Photo.of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has the gout and cannot come to Paris to view the "curious Experiments."
    (from original in Koninklijke Bibliotheek, 'sGravenhage.)
  - to Mrs [Margaret] Stevenson and [Mary] Hewson, 1780 December 7; L.Signed with initials. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Text of letter in W.T.Franklin's hand)
  - Letter to John Jay, 1781 January 15; Facsimile. 1p. 5-1/2x4-1/2.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    [From Robert F. Batchelder, Cat. no. 21, March 1978.]
    Franklin has been ill. Has accepted Jay's "bill." Mentions Mr. Carmichael. Franklin sending Jay some packets.
  - Letter to John Jay, 1781 Jan. 27; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 8,200.
  - Letter to [James] Searle, 1781 January 28; Photocopy of A.L.in 3rd P. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Will dine with him Tuesday.
    From Charles Hamilton auction catalogue, No. 98, New York, July 29, 1976, item 119.
  - Letter to Chere Amie [Mme. Golowkin], 1781 Feb. 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Transcribes paragraph from a Philadelphia newspaper relating to the Chev. de Chastellux.
    See Gilbert Chinard, B. Franklin and the mysterious Mme. G, APS Library Bulletin, 1946,p.49.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 Mar. 2; Photostat of L.S. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796
    Encloses resolutions of the Congress pertaining to John Paul Jones.
    Presented by Arthur Bloch, Dec.1952, who received photostat from F.B. Huntington.
  - Account with John Jay, 1781 April 12 - July 27; D.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to Col. Lawrens (sic), 1781 May 21; L.S. 1p., end. Mutilated.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Mr. Necker replaced by M. Joly de Fleury. Has been applied to for expenses on the Alliance. Presented by Mr. Samuel H. McVitty, March 1955.
  - Receipt for advance, 28 February 1778 also signed by Gilas Deane; Promissory note, 1781 July 2; D.S. 2p. 7-1/2x9.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    750,000 livres @5%/year the 1 January 1788, from date of advance, to French Royal treasury.
  - Letter to [Charles Gravier] Comte de Vergennes, 1781 July 6; Copy of D. 1p. 14x8-1/2.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Asks Vergennes to extend credit to U.S. for payment of debts. "...if we cannot go on with our Payments we are ruined."
  - Power of attorney to his brother. Joseph M. Fox: Paris, 1781 Sept. 28; DS, 3p. In French.; Fox George, d.1828
    Translation. 2p.
  - Letter to [John] Bondfield, 1781 October 25; L.S. 1p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has sent commission for the Brig Sally. Orders claret sent to Richard Bache.
    (In reply to Bonafield's of October 20 - F.P. 23,19)
  - Letter "To all Captains and Commanders [of the United States]", 1781 November 16; Photo.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Copy of D. and Italian translation of D. 3 items. Asks them to respect passports for ships travelling between Dover and Calais. Presented: A. pace; May 1961
    From originals in Biblioteca Estense of Modena, Codici e Mss Campori, Busta 209.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 Nov. 20; Bache, Benjamin Franklin
  - Promissory note, 1781 December 4; Photo, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. [Passy, B. Franklin.]
    For 816,000 livres, to be repaid with interest by the U.S. to his majesty's royal treasury by Jan. 1, 1788.
    Photograph gift of Joseph Rubinfine, March 24, 1983.
  - Liste des livres de M. Franklin apportes de la chambre dans le bureau le 31 Dbre 1781 [and] Liste des livres apportes au bureau le 8 Jr 1782, 1781 December 31-1782 January 8; Typescript 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - [Specimen sheet of various fonts in the collection of brass stencils bought from Bery in 1781.], ca.1781; D. with ms. Notes, lp.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Found in secret drawer of box containing brass stencils bought in Bache sele, June 1947.
    Reproduced in A.P.S. Proceedings, v.92,no.2,p.93; Library bulletin for 1948, p.93.
  - Letter to Capt. [John] Berry, 1782 January 24; L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth,8,370.
  - Letter to Benny [Bache], 1782 January 25; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 8,372.
  - Letter to Master Johannot [Cooper], 1782 January 25; A.L. 1p. Draft. 12-1/4x8. (see Franklin Papers.); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Hopes he is happy at school and does not want to change schools, for "A rolling Stone gathers no Moss."
  - Letters to Mme. Brillon, 1782 January 6; A.L. 3p. In French. "No.7"; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Replies to letter from Brillon family December 1781
    (see FP 56, no.79)
  - to B. Franklin, [1782 May 1 ?]; Fragment of an A.L.; Hewson, Mary
    (This item is printed in Stifler, p.166, with the notation that the original is in the University of Pennsylvania.
  - to [Mary] Hewson, 1782 May 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to D[avid] Hartley, 1782 May 13; L.S. 2p., end. seal.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 8,500.
  - Letter to Mme. A[nna] Ogle, 1782 May 24; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of Mrs. F.G. Richards of Princeton; presented by Julian P. Boyd, March 1948.
  - Letter to B[enjamin] Franklin, 1782 May 27; ALS, 3p. 8-7/8x7-3/8.; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    Interest in printing art, on continent,Eng. pressmen are "spoilt." Comment on war, Bill allowing King to conclude peace. Wants B.F. to help Sally Beckwith (daugh. of Gen.Beck.) Mentions Mr. Becket, Mrs.Strange, Dr. Wishart.
  - Letter to [Richard and Sarah Bache], 1782 June 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    News of Benny Bache in Geneva. Refers to Temple.
    Presented by Mrs.Elizabeth Du Bois Bache
    Aug. 4, 1924.
  - Letter to B[enjamin] Vaughan, 1782 July 10; T.c. of L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    The peace commission.
    From original in the possession of the Marquess of Lansdowne.
  - Letter to James Bowdoin, 1782 July 15; Copy of ALS, 1p 9-1/4x6.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces William Jones and John Paradise.
    (From Charles Hamilton Auction No. 57(April 20,1972).
  - Letter to [John Jay], 1782 August 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Encloses copy of extracts from Gen. Carleton's instructions received from Lord Shelburne through Mr. Vaughan. [Peace negotiations]
  - Letter to M. [Pierre] Colombe, 1782 Aug. 27; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. Acknowledges Colombe's letters of July 19 and August 19 relative to his return to America. Exchanges such as he desires are made in America.
  - Letter to [Bartolemeo(?)] Mesny, 1782 Sept. 11; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerning books sent him for sale.
    For addition al information pertaining to Franklin-Mesny correspondence, see: Kirkland. "A Franklin Footnote", Penna. Mag.of Hist.and Biog., vol. 73, 80-81.
    Additional correspondence on the books may be found in Franklin Papers in U. of P.
    See Franklin Papers, IX.186 for letter from Mesny to B.Franklin; May 20,1778.
  - Letter to [Philippe Denis] Pierres, 1782 Sept. 20; L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. Thanks for the publications as examples of his "Beautés Typographiques."
    Presented by Alice Bates through Charles W. Bates; June 1967.
  - Passport issued to Elkanah Watson, 1782 Sept. 7; PrDS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Passy press imprint. In French.
  - Order to "All captains and commanders of vessels of war, privateers and letters of marque belonging to the United States of America" to respect passports of certain English vessels which were to carry mail between Dover and Calais, 1782 November 16; D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Contains fine example of Franklin's seal. Right hand margin badly trimmed.
    Purchased from the American Autograph Shop, January 1939.
  - Letter to the Earl of Shelburne, 1782 November 26; T.c. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges a remedy for his "gravel" brought by Mr. [Benjamin ?] Vaughan.
  - Letter to R[ichard] Oswald, 1782 November 26; Photostat of L. 13p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (From original in possession of Ohio historical society).
    Printed: Smyth, VIII, 621ff.
  - Letter to Dr. Franklin; Warwick, 1782 Dec. 26; Photostat of A.L.S: Caty Greene 2p.; Greene, Catherine Ray
    Learned from the Court Segur that his wife often plays chess with Dr. Franklin. Sends letter by President Wheelock.
    From original in possession of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Printed: Roelker's Franklin-Greene Correspondence, p.119